Many say that one of your many strengths as a surrogate is your connection to young people.
I believe that to be true.
Now, voters between 18 and 29 years old stand out as disapproving of the way the Biden administration is handling the Israel-Hamas war.
They do not support sending weapons and money to Israel.
They are advocating for a humanitarian ceasefire.
How does the administration respond to the concerns of this very important part of the Democratic voter base?
So let's start with this.
And you're right, Sonny.
In fact, in the fall, I embarked on what I called a college tour and met with over 15,000 students across the country.
I just have to say I love Gen Z, by the way.
I think it's a spectacular generation.
But all of that to say, you're absolutely right.
I have talked with young people, many around the country, and I've heard them, I see them, and I understand.
I understand.
But I think it's important that while we understand where they're coming from, which I do, that we not lose sight of the context,
which is, let's just go back to October 7th, we can't deny the significance of a vicious, brutal attack that caused the-
I have to catch my breath.
I know that I, I know I shouldn't be surprised, but okay, let's get back.
Let's get back to the video.
Let's get back.
Molly, we're in danger, girl.
It's just brutal attack that caused the death of 1,200 innocent people, a lot of them young people who are just attending a concert.
Yeah.
Women who were brutally assaulted and raped.
And again, as someone who spent a lot of my career focused on those kinds of crimes, the horror of it.
And all of that to also then say, Israel has a right to defend itself.
We would.
And how it does matters.
There have been far too many innocent Palestinians that have been killed.
The president and I and many members of our administration have been very clear.
I've been on over, I think, 14, 15 calls that the president has had with Bibi Netanyahu about what Israel must do to protect innocent civilians.
We all want this to end as soon as possible.
And how it ends matters.
Nobody told me about this lady again.
Don't.
Because I saw it.
I saw it.
I was never really hype about this lady.
You know?
I was never really hype.
But I said, okay, we do need a Black woman VP.
And, you know, I was around a lot of Black women who were really like, yes, that's what we need.
And I rode with it.
And I really, she ain't never been it.
And if you think after seeing this that she still is, then you ain't it.
It is incredibly distressing that when we look at the horror of Trump, that this is what is presented to us as the alternative.
And that they are trotting her out as an alternative to the alternative.
Biden.
And this is what is being served.
And I know that y'all are like, Amanda, why are you doing this?
You're going to just further infuriate people and stop them from voting.
No, that's not the goal.
We need to be voting knowing exactly what the fuck we're voting for and who we're voting for so that we don't end up here again.
Because they rocked folks to sleep.
You know what?
They rocked us to sleep.
After that last 2020.
Even if they get back in office, they cannot be allowed to continue to behave in this fashion.
And you're going to need to vote strategically.
You're going to need to exist differently if you want to see this no longer be the only other option.
For the record, other countries have other parties.
In England, they have the Labour Party.
It's a party for the laborers.
It ideally works on behalf of making sure that legislation regards the laborers who are the majority of the country.
Then you have in Ireland, they literally have a party called the People Before Profits Party in Ireland.
So this idea of there only being a binary, y'all have to understand, like, it is not the way it is everywhere else.
The same way that they don't even collect trash the same way everywhere else.
It's just that in America, we're taught that the American way is the only way and the best way.
And the only way that's going to change is if we start considering and putting action behind another way.
I know you hear me say this, and many of you are saying,
Amanda, if you encourage people to vote third party, then you are actually going to give votes to Trump.
You're giving votes to the Republicans.
I'm not encouraging people to do anything other than to start thinking about what they're doing in a different way.
Because the way that we've been operating has not been effective.
But if we continue to only think within these very small boxes, then the only thing we're going to get is whatever can fit in those very small boxes.
Meaning it's a very small amount of change.